ALEX NG'ANG'A WAWERU

P. O. BOX 752-20100, Nairobi, Kenya.

Cell: +254 716570983.

E-mail: ngashalex8@gmail.com

**Portfolio**: <a href="https://portfolio-1frp.onrender.com/">https://portfolio-1frp.onrender.com/</a>

**GitHub**: <a href="https://github.com/AleWaweru">https://github.com/AleWaweru</a>

**OBJECTIVE AND ASPIRATIONS** 

To contribute to the fulfillment of the organization's goals and objectives through hard work and a team player mindset.

To develop my skills and experience through exposure and being open to new ideas.

To participate in Software development projects for my clients/employers and contribute to the growth of their

organization/companies.

PROFESSIONAL ACCOMPLISHMENTS

PHP, JAVASCRIPT, REACT, BOOTSTRAP, NEXT JS, RAILS, SQL, EXPRESS JS, NODE JS, MONGO DB RUBY

ON RAILS web developer and MySQL, POSTGRESQL, database interaction. With this, I have been actively building

front-end projects for different clients, digital marketing, and account management.

Experienced UX designer.

Mobile app Development using react native and Flutter

Also use of GITFLOW, webpack, APIs, and Unit Test.

Familiar with REST API and Kanban board.

Experience Using Git commands.

Successfully build a website for Gemstone Constructions and Services

Actively building projects that are available in GitHub for review.

**WORK EXPERIENCE** 

**2023 – Present Internship (JUUBIX)** 

During my internship at JUUBIX a London-based fintech startup company, I excelled in remote pair

programming, quickly adapting to new roles and technologies. I proudly became proficient in Next.js, a vital

skill gained while working on an assigned project. Additionally, I played a pivotal role in developing the main

app, a significant achievement in this extensive project. This experience has shaped me into an agile team player with strong technical capabilities.

#### 2020 - 2022

Worked as a freelance full-stack web developer, consistently using WordPress, HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, PHP, and MySQL. With this, I have successfully built websites and apps with the client's interaction interface and managed websites for multiple clients.

(2017-2020) Freelancer - Did freelancing, building websites (WordPress), digital marketing for various clients, and product promotion.

### **ACADEMIC BACKGROUND**

(2022 till now) MICROVERSE - Ongoing remote course in software engineering at Microverse Institute USA. Studying:

- JavaScript
- React Js
- Ruby
- Redux

(2019-2020) FREE CODE CAMP- Did free code camp certification in HTML, CSS, and PHP

#### (2013 – 2017) MASINDE MULIRO UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY

- Bachelor's Degree in Natural Sciences

## **CAREER ASPIRATION**

I aim to identify and implement sustainable means of livelihood, working collaboratively with colleagues and other like-minded parties while maintaining the highest possible professional competency and intellectual proficiency.

## **HOBBIES AND PERSONAL INTERESTS**

- · Playing musical instruments
- · Travelling and exploring nature

- Interacting and socializing with people
- Community empowerment

# **REFEREES**

Mr. Charles Njuguna	Conard Mayaka	Joseph Waiguru	
Business Consultant	Full Stack developer at Safaricom PLC.	Full Stack Software Developer	
Email: charlesknjuguna@gmail.com Mobile: +254722991652	EMAIL: mayakaconard@gmail.com	Mobile:+254710653477	